[MUSIC]
[음악]
Cool, so this is the data we're working with.
이게 우리가 작업할 데이터죠
It's a pretty neat data set, and let's explore it a little bit more.
상당히 깔끔한 데이터 세트인데 좀 더 살펴봅시다
So, in the lectures, Emily talked about building word counts.
강의에서 에밀리가 단어수 구축과
And some of the challenges with word count.
그에 따르는 어려움에 대해 알아봤었죠
So let's start by taking a quick look at our word counts.
단어수를 짧게 훑어보는 것으로 시작하죠
So for example, let's #Get the word
#오바마 문서의
counts for the Obama article.
단어수 세기
So we have an article on Wikipedia about Barack Obama.
바락 오바마에 대한 위키피디아 문서입니다
And what we're gonna do first is just take a quick look at the word counts for
먼저 빠르게 문서의 단어수를
that article.
세어보죠
So I'm going to take this Obama variable that we created, and
생성한 오바마 변수에
I'm going to add a new column to it called word_count.
단어수라는 열을 추가합니다
So this is going to store the word count for Barack Obama.
단어수를 담을 공간입니다
And we can do that by just calling.
단어수를 세려면 간단히
You could write, as we showed in the classifications sentiment analysis
분류 강의의 감성분석 노트북에서 했듯이
notebook, you could write the function yourself to compute the word counts.
단어수 세기를 위한 함수를 스스로 작성해도 되지만
But we just have one ready for us in the text analytics toolbox.
텍스트 분석 도구상자에 친절히 준비되어 있습니다
So we just gonna use it to get started quickly.
빠른 시작을 위해 이걸 쓰죠
So we just call count_words.
count_words를 호출합니다
See this count_ngrams, we're just gonna count words, which in the unit grams,
여기 count_ngrams 보이시죠 우리는 그냥 단어수를 쓸 건데,
single words.
유니그램, 즉 단어 하나죠
And as input, we're gonna
입력으로 오바마 텍스트를
give it the Obama text.
넣습니다
So I've now done it.
이제 됐죠
And let's take a quick look.
잠시 살펴봅시다
Let's just print the Obama word count.
오바마 단어수를 출력합니다
And here we go.
됐지요
We've now printed the Obama word count.
오바마 단어수를 출력했습니다
And you see that operations appeared once, represent appears one,
operations 한 번, represent 한 번,
office appears two, unemployed appears one, and so on for various words.
office 두 번, unemployed 한 번 등장합니다
And it's not super intuitive here.
이것만으론 딱히 와닿지 않습니다
So we're gonna play with this a little bit, and in the process, I'm gonna show
이 데이터를 다루게 될 텐데, 그전에
you a cute little data engineering trick that might be useful in other areas.
다른 데서도 써먹을 만한 데이터 공학 요령을 하나 알려드리죠
So let's, what we're gonna
다음은
do next is ##Sort the word count for
##오바마 문서의
the Obama article.
검토할 겁니다
Now, here's something to understand a little bit better, if you notice the word
이해를 돕기 위해 설명하자면
counts is really a dictionary this is the kind of the Python dictionary.
단어수는 단순히 파이썬 사전에 불과합니다
You are given a key, in this case, it's the word.
키가 주어지고, 여기선 단어죠
For example, Honolulu where he was born, weather, marriage and so on.
그가 태어난 호놀룰루, 날씨, 결혼 등입니다
And then, he has a value of 1, 2, 3, 5, 30, which is the count,
그리고 1, 2, 3, 5, 30 같은 총계가
how often that word appeared.
각 단어의 빈도를 나타냅니다
And so what we're going to do is sort this.
이걸 정렬하겠습니다
And to sort those words, we have to turn it into a table where one column
단어를 정렬하려면 첫 번째 열은 단어, 즉 사전의 키이고,
is the word, the key of the dictionary, and the second column is the count.
두 번째 열은 총계인 표 형태로 변환해야 합니다
And then we're going to sort that table.
그런 다음 표를 정렬합니다
So, the way to do this, this famous way to learn Python, but
파이썬으로 이를 달성하는 방법은 다양하지만
let me show you a quick little trick that you will find useful.
간단한 요령을 하나 보여드리죠
So I'm gonna createa new table called the, obama_word_count_table.
obama_word_count_table이란 표를 생성합니다
And what I'm gonna do is take this Obama and I'm just gonna select here,
오바마 표의 모든 열에서
out of all the columns in the Obama table, I'm gonna select the, word_count.
word_count를 선택합니다
Because this will make the printing a little neater.
이렇게 하면 출력이 좀 더 깔끔해지죠
But you could have done that with the whole table too.
물론 전체 표를 출력해도 됩니다
And then, I'm gonna call a function called stack.
그런 다음 stack 함수를 호출합니다
And this function stack is extremely useful.
이 stack 함수는 무척 유용합니다
It takes one column of an SFrame that contains a dictionary, and
사전이 들어있는 SFrame의 열을
stacks it one of top of each other into multiple columns.
계속해서 쌓아 여러 열로 만듭니다
In this case, two columns.
이 경우 열 둘이지요
One for word, and the other one for count.
단어가 하나, 총계가 하나입니다
So we're gonna stack a particular column called word_count,
word_count이란 열을 쌓습니다
the one that we really care about.
우리에게 필요한 열이죠
And it generates some new columns.
그리고 새로운 열을 만듭니다
So we have to call them, give them a name.
호칭해야 하니 이름을 지어주죠
So new_column_name, in this case there are two of them.
new_column_name에 두 개가 들어가는데
One I'm gonna call, word.
하나는 단어고
And another one, I'm just going to call count.
다른 하나는 총계입니다
And if I execute this and we take a look at this table,
실행해서 표를 보면
Obama word count table.head just the first few lines.
obama_word_count_table.head로 처음 몇 줄만 출력하면
You'll see it shows words normalize, sought, combat, but it's not sorted.
normalize, sought, combat 등이 출력되는데 정렬이 되어있지 않습니다
It's not a sorted table.
정렬된 표가 아니죠
So what we do next is just take this table and just sort it by the count.
다음으로는 총계 기준으로 표를 정렬합니다
And we've seen this before, but it's pretty simple.
예전에 봤었죠 아주 간단합니다
So I'm gonna take the Obama count table, and I'm gonna call the sort function.
obama_count_table에서 sort 함수를 호출합니다
And I'm gonna sort it by the count column.
count를 인자로 주고요
Sort by count.
총계 기준으로 정렬
And I'm gonna say ascending=false.
오름차순을 거짓으로 설정합니다
So, instead of sorting in an ascending order, one, two, three,
1,2,3으로 이어지는 오름차순 대신에
like we'd normally sort, we're gonna sort in a descending order.
내림차순으로 정렬하는 거죠
Three, two, one.
3, 2, 1
So, if I press Enter, you'll see the most common word is the,
엔터를 누르면 가장 흔한 단어는 the,
followed by in, followed by and, of, to, his, eventually Obama.
그다음 in, and, of, to, his, Obama 순이네요
And so, act, a, he.
그리고 act, a, he가 나오고요
So those are not that informative.
별로 도움이 되는 정보는 아닙니다
And in the lectures, when we were working with Emily on them, she covered the issue
강의에서 에밀리가 이런 도움이 안 되는 단어가
that these uninformative words can drown out the important words.
주요 단어를 밀어내는 현상에 대해 다뤘죠
And that's why we introduced the notion of tfidf.
TF-IDF의 개념을 소개하는 계기가 이거였습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]